# **AKINOLA OLUTOLA**

7/9, Olutola Street, Berger, Lagos, olutolamoses@gmail.com, +2347084052319

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A 2+ year experience with a growth mindset and passion for solving real life problems through software applications. I have applied myself to build both back-end and front-end software applications in JavaScript and its many frameworks. I have collaborated in teams on several projects while also embodying a Do-It-Yourself (DIY) mindset to learn and implement innovative solutions.

#### SKILLS/COMPETENCIES

Heroku

Python

Vue (Options API and SFC's)

NodeJS/Express

Selenium

HTML/CSS/SCSS

MongoDB/Mongoose

Git

JavaScript/Typescript

### **EXPERIENCE**

Stutern | Lagos, Nigeria

Software Engineer

March 2022 - till date

- Developed several technical solutions within agile environment and made changes based on stakeholder's feedback.
- Collaborated with different project stakeholders to come with up technical solutions to real life problems with effected changes based on product manager feedback.
- Wrote and maintained API documentations with swagger.

Innovation Lead

Guaranty Trust Bank | Lagos, Nigeria

Jan 2020 – August 2022

- Led a team across various banking divisions to propose innovative solutions to serve customers better in response to Covid-19.
- Ensured effective communication amongst team members and maintained information flow despite stiff business schedules amongst team members.
- Solutions were voted best with high adoption rate, cost effective with high possibility of revenue generation.
- Strategic creation off company's goals and objective, effective client management and relationship building Front-End Developer

Self-Employed

July 2021 - November 2021

- Partnered with UX designers to develop a web-based single page application.
- Replicated popular front-end designs such as Netflix and Jumia with pure HTML, CSS, Vanilla JavaScript and webpack.
- Learnt a JavaScript framework and built web applications with the Vue options API.

#### **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION**

MSc. Artificial Intelligence and Data Analytics - Current
Bradford University

BSc. Anatomy
Babcock University

Python Fundamentals
Udacity

Front End Development
Pirple

July 2021
Pirple

Mobile Web Developer Google Developers

May 2022